一定能贏
Yeah. We got this.
今晚可是光榮的拳王之夜 羅伊
...here at the MGM Grand tonight, Roy.
你知道嗎 阿多尼斯·奎迪之前惜敗於「俊小子」裏基·康蘭
And, you know, when Adonis Creed lost to "Pretty" Ricky Conlan,
但他的橫空出世 引起了大家的好奇
he was really a curiosity more than anything else.
那真是一場激烈的比賽
But that was an epic fight,
從那以後 他一口氣取得了六連勝的戰績
and since then, he's reeled off six straight wins,
而今晚他又將對戰「特技演員」丹尼·惠勒
and tonight attempts against Danny "The Stuntman" Wheeler
馬克斯·凱勒曼 羅伊·瓊斯
水平等級
23勝1負 賽記 33勝0負
28 年齡 35
185厘米 身高 182厘米
97公斤 體重 95公斤
182厘米 臂展 180厘米
阿多尼斯·奎迪 丹尼·惠勒
共同競爭世界重量級拳王寶座
to become the heavyweight champion of the world.
值得一提的是 奎迪在上次與惠勒的熱身賽中
It bears mentioning that Creed actually wagered his Mustang
把自己的福特野馬都賭輸了 羅伊
before their sparring session, Roy.
據說這輛福特野馬 今晚又被惠勒當成了賭注
And rumor has it that same Mustang is on the line again tonight.
好了 都出去吧 我們走
Okay, everybody out. Let's go.
- 還好嗎 - 好
- Feel good? - Mmm-hmm.
記住要一直出右拳 好嗎
Yeah. Remember to keep your right hand up, okay?
他的左拳和右拳一樣厲害
His left is just as strong as his right.
好
- Yep. - Yeah.
你去大便過了嗎
那就好
- Mmm-hmm. - Mmm-hmm. Okay, good.
保持平常心就行 好嗎
It's just another fight, okay?
你一定能贏的
You got this.
奎迪隊
從台下到台上只有三個台階
You know, there's only three steps into that ring.
三個而已
Just three.
可今晚它們會像山一樣高不可攀
And tonight, it's gonna look as high as a mountain.
當你鑽過圍繩之後
And when you climb through them ropes,
會立刻陷入孤立無援的境地
it's gonna be the loneliest place in the world
因為站在你對面的拳手
because you're gonna be in there with another fighter
只想把你擊倒
who wants to take you out.
現在你必須問問自己
So now, you gotta ask yourself,
你來這兒到底是為了不辜負別人
are you here to prove something to other people
還是為了無愧於自己
or prove something to yourself?
我想無愧於自己
To myself.
很好
Right.
現在換我來問你問題
Now, let me ask you something.
你問
What?
你頭髮怎麼了
What's with the hair?
我仔細梳了梳 今天可是大日子
I combed it. It's a special night.
你是不是該操心點別的事 小滑頭
Shouldn't you be thinking about something else, wise guy?
好了 去證明自己
Now, you can go prove it.
把你那輛野馬給贏回來
Now go get your Mustang back.
兩位拳手在第四回合真是打得難解難分
These guys have really been mixing it up here in the fourth.
目前 年輕氣盛的奎迪壓制了經驗老到的惠勒
So far, Creed's youth outweighing Wheeler's experience.
逼他後退 加油 兄弟
Let's go! Let's go, baby. Let's o!
阿多尼斯·奎迪的這場比賽最振奮人心的地方
Maybe the most amazing part of Adonis Creed's journey, Roy...
別放鬆 穩點
Don't drop that guard! Sit.
就在於他今晚的搏殺
...is that tonight, he fights...
繼續出拳
Keep your hands up!
是為了接過他的教練洛奇·巴爾博亞
...for the same belt held by both his trainer, Rocky Balboa,
和他的父親 偉大的阿波羅·奎迪 都嬴過的那條金腰帶
and his father, the great Apollo Creed.
惠勒好像要發力反擊了 這一幕似曾相識 羅伊
Wheeler seems to be waking up. We've seen this before, Roy.
一旦發現機會 惠勒就會變得無人能擋
When Wheeler smells blood, he really turns it on.
再來 繼續再打
Come on back.
加油 多尼
Come on, D!
放在三年前 奎迪就輸定了
Three years ago, that's a knockout.
可如今惠勒的力量已經不如以往 奎迪肯定也察覺到了這點
Wheeler's power just isn't the same, and no doubt Creed can sense it.
他不行了 咬緊他
You got him. Stay on him!
奎迪是志在必得啊 現在簡直卯足了全力
Creed's on a mission, really pressing the issue now.
他揮出了一記雷霆萬鉤的左勾拳
And a big left hook lands flush!
奎迪對惠勒如影隨形 持續出擊 不躲也不停
Creed staying in the pocket, Max. Moving, not running.
再加把勁 出拳
Come on, now! Hands up! Hands up!
兩位拳手真的都拼盡了全力
These two men are really going at it.
幹掉他 多尼
Tell him, Donnie!
又一記左勾拳 惠勒連連後退
Another left hook drives Wheeler back.
加油 兄弟
Come on, baby!
奎迪冷不丁從空隙裏揮出一記上勾拳
That was a sneaky little uppercut on the inside,
惠勒受到了重創 羅伊
and Wheeler's hurt by that, Roy.
沒錯 他的腿抖得厲害
Yeah, that wobbled his legs pretty bad.
- 又是一記重擊 - 出拳 出拳
- Another big shot! - Hold him, hold him, hold him!
奎迪壓制住惠勒了 馬克斯
Creed has him in trouble, Max.
惠勒正在奮力抵抗 但是
Wheeler's doing what he can...
惠勒倒下了
Wheeler is down!
惠勒倒在了拳台上
Wheeler has hit the canvas!
你就趴著吧 小子
Now stay there, boy!
我奎迪才是贏家
Creed taught you!
讓他把車鑰匙還我
Come and give me my keys!
快起來 加油 兄弟
Get up! Come on, baby!
快起來
Get up, get up!
- 惠勒掙扎著想站起來 - 一
- Wheeler, trying to get up. - One!
- 趴著吧 - 二
- Stay down! - Two!
但不知能否趕在倒計時結束前起身
I don't know if he makes this count, Roy.
三
Three!
四
Four!
五
Five!
六
Six!
七
Seven!
八
Eight!
九
Nine!
結束了
That's it. That's it.
比賽結束了 馬克斯
And it's over, Max.
難以置信 阿多尼斯·奎迪
No way! Adonis Creed...
還我車鑰匙
Give me my keys!
他登上了世界重量級拳賽的拳王寶座
...is the heavyweight champion of the world.
你知道你成拳王了嗎
You know what you just did?
知道
Yeah.
寶貝 你知道發生什麼了嗎
Baby, you know what just happened?
大家可以想想這個年輕人的出身
When you think of where this kid has come from,
以他的起點是不可能當上拳手的 羅伊
the most unlikely beginning for a fighter, Roy.
按照他的成長路徑
Growing up the way he did
他能這樣一步一步地登上拳王寶座
to make it to the top of boxing in this way...
惠勒隊
可以說是史無前例
It's unprecedented!
奎迪 奎迪 奎迪
Creed! Creed! Creed!
成為頭號拳王競爭者是一回事
It's one thing to be the number one contender.
真正成為拳王則完全是另一回事
It's a whole other thing to be champion.
今晚就是他稱霸拳壇 續寫拳王傳奇的第一步
This is the first step to building a legacy of his own,
我已經迫不及待想看到阿多尼斯·奎迪 會有怎樣的未來
and I can hardly wait to see what's next for Adonis Creed.
這個怎麼樣
I mean, what do you think?
這
That's...
這真是太漂亮了
That is beautiful.
- 是吧 - 是
- Right? - Yeah.
我們得快點
But we gotta hurry up.
她隨時都可能洗完澡出來的
I mean, she's about to get out the shower any second.
多尼 你之前怎麼都不告訴我呢
Yo, Donnie, why didn't you tell me about this before?
我又不確定能不能贏
I didn't know if I was gonna win.
和能不能贏有什麼關係
What's that got to do with it?
我說不好
I don't know.
好了 你教我怎麼做
Look, just tell me what I should do.
你得單膝下跪
You get down on one knee.
這一套還沒過時嗎
People still do that shit?
發短信求婚也不是不行
You can always send her a text.
拜託 大叔 我是認真的 好嗎
Come on, Unc, I'm being serious, all right?
你怎麼求婚的
I mean, what did you say?
- 跟艾德裏安嗎 - 對
- To Adrian? - Yeah.
那是很久前的事了
It was a long time ago.
我們去了動物園 那時還是冬天 下著雪
We were at the zoo. It was winter. It was snowing.
空氣非常清新
Everything smelled fresh.
有一隻老虎 背上落著一層雪花
There was this tiger. He had snow on its back.
- 它在遠處走來走去 然後 - 好了 我知道了
- And he's walking in the background. - Okay, I get it. I get it.
你就說你怎麼求的
Just tell me what you said.
我正要說這段呢
Well, I was getting to that part.
我當時就問她
What I said is...
會不會特別反感跟我結婚
I asked if she would not mind marrying me very much,
我這麼說就等於含蓄地暗示 她是我的一切
which is kind of a dumb way of saying she's my world,
是她拯救了那個原本會墮落的我
and she made me better than I deserved to be.
你懂的
You know?
是這樣
Yeah.
聽著 你就乾脆別想太多
Listen, why don't you just turn off your brain
把真正的心裏話說給她聽
and let your heart do the talking.
敞開心門
Click.
你會如願的
You'll do good.
- 不用想太多 - 沒錯
- Turn my brain off? - Yeah.
好的
- Okay. - Mmm-hmm.
好的 明白
- All right. - All right.
沒錯 我知道了
All right, I'm on it.
大叔
- Hey, Unc. - Mmm.
你沒事吧
You good?
沒事 好著呢 謝謝
Yeah, real good. Thank you.
- 真的挺好 - 好
- Great. - All right.
嫁給我 好嗎
Will you marry me?
聽著 比安
Listen, B.
我們已然在一起好幾年了
I know we've been dating for a few years now,
而且我們倆相處得挺合拍
and it's just something about us that just click.
我不知道怎麼解釋 可是
I don't know how to explain it,
你陪在我身邊的那種感覺其實讓我
but the feeling I get when you're by my side is a feeling
已經戒不掉了
that I can't live without.
我知道很瘋狂 但是我就是想跟你說 那個
I know I sound crazy, but, look, I guess what I'm trying to say is...
嫁給我 好嗎
Will you marry me?
我還是很餓 寶貝
I'm still hungry, babe,
也不知道怎麼了
I don't know why.
你認真的嗎
Are you for real, D?
是 我很認真
Yeah, I'm for real.
別鬧 不要耍我
No, stop playin'.
我沒耍你
I ain't playin'.
你沒聽見 對吧
You didn't hear any of that?
聽見什麼
None of what?
我沒聽見什麼
None of what, D?
你說了什麼
What did you say?
你已經知道我說什麼了
Nothing that you don't already know.
提醒我一下
Remind me.
我說了我很愛你
I said that I love you,
還有我很需要你
and that I need you.
多尼 你知道你在幹什麼嗎
D, do you know what you're doing right now?
我算是知道吧
I mean, yeah, kind of.
什麼叫算是
What do you mean, "kind of"?
寶貝
Babe!
我是
I mean...
想跟你說心裏話
To keep it real with you, B,
我只想跟你
you're the only person
分享我人生的點點滴滴
I wanna share my moments with.
所以 比安卡·泰勒
So, Bianca Taylor,
嫁給我好嗎
will you marry me?
嗯
Yo.
- 那這算答應了 - 是的
- "Yo"? Is that a yes? - Yes.
這算答應了麼
It's yes?
是的
Yes!
好
Yeah.
維克托
Viktor.
這小子狀態不錯啊
Our boy's looking good.
好消息都聽說了吧
I'm sure you heard the good news.
機會來了
It's time.
你有沒有想過搬回洛杉磯去住
You ever thought about going back to LA?
算了吧 你可是費城人
Please, you're a Philly girl.
話是這麼說 但是
Yeah, I guess,
那邊有更大的發展空甸
but it'd be nice to have more space.
再說 你媽媽也在那邊
And your mom's out there...
還有不少唱片公司
And them labels, too.
我有機會讓更多人聽到我的音樂
Could help me get my music out to more people.
我總感覺我在費城發展到頭了 你懂吧
I don't know, I feel like I've done everything I could in Philly, you know?
我能做音樂的時間也不多了
Time ain't exactly on my side, you know?
那洛奇怎麼辦
What about Rocky?
洛奇有自己的生活啊
Rocky has his life, D.
我們也得考慮未來
We gotta start ours.
今天可真冷啊 艾德裏安 真的很冷
It's a cold one today, Adrian, that's for sure.
我之前給咱們的兒子博比打了幾次電話
I tried calling our son Bobby a few times.
但是每次他要接的時候我就又給掛了
But I'd hang up every time he was about to pick up
因為說實話我不知道要說什麼
because, to tell you the truth, I didn't know what to say to him.
艾德裏安·巴爾博亞 生於1950年3月10日
卒於2002年9月11日
要是他新生活過得好好的
What if he's moving on,
我以前沒管過也 現在卻去插一腳
and I'm like this chunk of yesterday trying to be today?
也挺不合適的
I just don't fit in.
可我到底該怎麼做呢
I mean, what am I supposed to do?
敲開他的門直接說 你好嗎
Knock on his door and say, "Hey, how you doing?
咱們有多久沒見了 這不太好吧
"What's it been, a lot of years?" I don't know.
我想你
I miss you.
麥克斯餐廳 酒吧
自從你贏回這輛車就一直很興奮啊
You've been hype ever since you got this jawn.
你說什麼呢
What are you talking about?
就是這個笑容
That smile right there.
都笑開花了
You're cheezin'.
我爸就留給我這麼輛車
It's the only thing my pops left me.
當然了 還有拳頭
I mean, that and these hands.
- 你沒說過這事 - 是
- You never told me that. - Yeah.
你怎麼會藏著這麼多秘密啊 多尼
What's up with you and these secrets, Don?
你怎麼樣 好
How're you doing? All right, all right.
艾德裏安餐廳
看這邊
But look at this, here.
- 你怎麼樣 - 你好
- How you doing? - Hey.
- 伊莎貝爾 - 洛奇
- Hey, Isabelle. - Hey, Rock.
聽著 那邊坐了一個大塊頭 一直在等你
Hey, listen. Some big guy's sitting over there, waiting for you.
他說你知道他是誰
He said you'll know who he is.
拳王
Yo, champ.
你得跟這傢伙打 兄弟 打得他心服口服
You gotta take that fight, man. Shut this dude up.
不會吧 惠勒還沒認輸嗎
No, Wheeler still talking shit?
還不到再跟他打的時候
It's a little early for a rematch, bro.
電視聲開大點
Hey, turn the TV up.
拳壇歷史上的悲劇又將兩代人扯到了一起
...and the tragic history that connects them.
是你
That you?
這些照片不錯
Nice pictures.
是 都照得挺好
Yeah, they're okay.
但是裏面沒有我的
No pictures of me.
沒有 我這兒確實沒你的照片
No, there's no pictures of that.
你怎麼在費城
Why are you in Philly?
你不知道嗎
You don't know?
維克托·德拉龍向阿多尼斯·奎迪宣戰
Ukrainian boxer Viktor Drago appeared today in Philadelphia
於今日現身美國費城
to issue a very public challenge
公開宣佈自己要挑戰最近加冕的世界重量級拳王阿多尼斯·奎迪
to recently crowned heavyweight champion Adonis Creed.
拳賽經紀人巴迪·瑪塞勒日前為此召開了記者招待會
A press conference was held earlier by boxing promoter Buddy Marcelle.
我們專程來費城就是告訴你這不是開玩笑
We came all the way to Philly to let you know it's serious.
我身邊這位可不像丹尼·惠勒那麼弱
Now, this man here, he ain't no Danny Wheeler.
而且說實話奎迪是在惠勒巔峰期過了三年後才贏的
And let's be honest, Creed fought him three years too late, anyway.
贏了不稀奇
Easy match.
你在這個國家備受愛戴
People in this country love you.
但在我的國家
But Russia,
德拉戈之名無可撼動
no one touch Drago name.
可是那一晚的比賽改變了一切
Everything changed that night.
你看 那件事都已經
Look, you know, that's like
已經是八百年前的事了
a million years ago.
可對我卻仿如昨日
Like yesterday to me.
你大老遠到我這兒來就想說這個嗎
So, you came all the way over here to tell me that?
阿波羅·奎迪的兒子剛剛捧回金腰帶
It's no coincidence that Ivan Drago's son shows up
伊凡·德拉戈的兒子就出現 這恐怕不是巧合
right after Apollo Creed's son claims the belt.
這是奎迪家對德拉戈家的復仇之戰
This is Creed versus Drago.
也是一場萬眾期待的世紀之戰
This is the fight the whole world wants to see.
阿多尼斯理應接受挑戰
And this is the fight he should take.
除非他害怕歷史會在自己身上重演
Unless he's afraid of history repeating itself.
這段歷史指的是1985年那場殘酷的比賽
That history being the infamous 1985 match
傳奇拳手阿波羅·奎迪在比賽中
in which boxing legend Apollo Creed was killed by Russian fighter
死在了俄羅斯拳手伊凡·德拉戈的拳下
Ivan Drago.
而阿波羅的教練洛奇·巴爾博亞
Apollo's trainer Rocky Balboa was heavily criticized
也因未能及時叫停比賽 遭受到了巨大的譴責
for failing to stop that fight.
多尼 寶貝
D. Baby.
他們就是在炒作而己
It's a publicity stunt.
這種事別放心上
Don't worry about that.
後來
And let's not forget,
在同一年 德拉戈又被巴爾博亞所擊敗 而且是在自己的家門口 俄羅斯
later that year, Balboa defeated Drago in his own backyard, Russia.
就因為你 我失去了一切
Because of you, I lose everything.
祖國
Country.
我的尊嚴
Respect.
還有妻子
Wife.
你有沒有見過烏克蘭的流浪狗
You ever see stray dogs in Ukraine?
它們日日夜夜忍饑挨餓
They go for days with no food.
還要受人類唾棄 一無所有
People spit on them. They have nothing.
無家可歸
No home.
它們一心只想著生存 還有戰鬥
Only will to survive, to fight.
我有個兒子
I have son.
他只會用拳頭
All he knows
拚命
is this.
我的兒子會打敗你的徒弟
My son will break your boy.
我有點累了
Been a long day.
就說到這兒吧
I think we're done here.
我們這裏可不會讓流浪狗到處亂吠
Because around here we put strays away.
這張照片不錯
It's good picture.
我就猜到你會在這裏
I kind of figured you'd be here.
我之前不停地給你打電話 可是一直就沒有人接
You know, I tried calling and calling, but nobody picked up or anything.
你不覺得剛比完就訓練 有點操之過急嗎
Kind of early to be training, don't you think, after a fight?
我是想醒醒腦
Just trying to clear my head.
我明白了
I get that.
這反正比看心理醫生便宜
Cheaper than a shrink, that's for sure.
多尼 好了 我知道發生了什麼
Hey, Don, come on. I heard what's going on.
但是你不能讓他們擾亂你
But you can't let them get inside.
不過你的心情我也理解
But I know how you're feeling.
- 是嗎 - 真的 我懂
- Oh, do you? - Yeah, I do.
那些恩怨都過去那麼久 跟你一點關係都沒有
What happened a long time ago, that ain't got nothing to do with you.
聽著 那場比賽是阿波羅自己想打的 懂嗎
Listen, that fight is what Apollo wanted, all right?
雖然不該發生
It shouldn't have happened.
可這是命
But it did.
別再糾結了
And you gotta let it go.
放下
Come on.
你看過維克托比賽嗎
You've seen him fight, though?
我在體育頻道和其他節目上看過
I've seen him on sports TV and stuff like that.
他很壯 可惜太嫩
He's big, but he's raw.
他可打不過你這麼老到的拳手 我敢肯定
He ain't no mean machine like you are, that's for sure.
這樣好了
You know what?
我幫你振作一下 今天你算是撞大運了
I'm gonna cheer you up, 'cause today's gonna be your lucky day.
提前給你個聖誕禮物吧
Christmas just came early for you,
我來親自為你扶沙袋 幸運的小子
'cause I'm gonna hold the bag, lucky guy.
- 不 幸運的是你 - 為什麼
- No, you're the one who's lucky. - How's that?
因為我讓你有幸為我扶沙袋
'Cause I'm gonna let you hold the bag for me.
不錯
Yo.
這一拳更好
That's it. That's better.
世界級拳王 世界拳擊理事會
奎迪挨了好幾拳 看來比賽快結束了
Creed taking major hits. This could be over soon.
奎迪倒地了 而且他可能受了重傷
Creed is down! And he could be badly hurt.
阿波羅倒在地上沒有反應了
Apollo on the floor looking unresponsive.
情況似乎不妙
This doesn't look good.
他完全不能動了
There is no movement.
2月23日 菲爾莫爾禮堂 比安卡
我年少時 眸中燦若晨星
♪ Glitter in my eyes And I was young
他們說我曾經桀驁不馴
♪ Know what they say I ran away from home
謝謝你讓我瞭解這個世界
♪ I thank you I learned the world
他們說我的心早已支離破碎
♪ They think I'm a broken girl
我只是喜歡這種迷失的感覺
♪ I think I'm in love with lost
她聲音真棒
Amazing voice.
我心已碎 但起碼它跳動過
♪ My heart cracked But at least it's touched ♪
抱歉 我在媒體前有點誇張
Sorry for the theatrics.
可大家就愛看好戲
But people like a good show.
你這招太賤了 夥計
That was a grimy move, brah.
我不是針對你
Ain't nothing personal.
我對拳壇的現狀是沒什麼自豪感
Can't say I'm proud of what our sport's become,
可世道就是這樣
but that's the game.
隨便你怎麼說
Call it whatever you want.
反正在我聽來你就是想賺錢
Sounds to me like you just trying to get paid.
錢只是順便賺來的
The money is a side effect.
阿里那場世紀大戰的盛況可不是憑空出現的
"The Rumble in the Jungle" didn't just manifest itself.
得有人組織策劃
Somebody had to make it happen.
把願望變成現實
Will it into existence.
你要當這人 是吧
Oh, yeah, that's supposed to be you, huh?
你在這圈子還見過誰是真正關心拳手利益的
You see anybody else standing here with a care in their heart?
你我想要的都一樣
I want the same thing you want.
是嗎 我要什麼
Yeah? What's that?
在拳壇的歷史上
In the history of boxing,
一共出現過77位重量級的拳王
there have been 77 heavyweight champions.
這你知道嗎
You know that?
你覺得大眾認識幾個
But how many do you think they know?
四個嗎
Four?
五個嗎
Five?
有金腰帶不夠
The belt ain't enough.
你得有故事 能讓大眾長時間津津樂道
You need a narrative. Something that sticks to the ribs.
你父親 他就很懂
Your dad, he knew that.
我勸你還是好自為之
Do yourself a favor, brah,
趁早收手別惹禍
and quit while you ahead.
你想明哲保身
Self-preservation.
至少這點你比你老爸強
At least you got that over your old man.
是洛奇吹耳邊風攔著你吧
That must be Rocky whispering in your ear.
我是認真的
I'm serious.
她的聲音真不錯
Amazing voice.
謝謝 菲爾莫爾
Yo, thank you, Fillmore.
非常感謝
For real though, thank you.
你怎麼樣 小子
How you doing, kid?
我們談談吧
We gotta talk.
那咱們散散步 透透氣
Let's take a walk and get some air.
好嗎 這屋裏有點悶
Okay? Kind of stuffy in here.
你看那燈
Look at that light.
那玩意兒已經壞了好幾年了
That thing's been broken for a couple of years.
我都要煩死了
It's driving me crazy.
市政局不給修 也不理我
City won't fix it or nothing.
燈亮不起來
What good is a light
那還有什麼用啊
that don't light, right?
這事挺逗 但這麼一看 也夠傻的
Kind of funny, but it's stupid, too.
我要接受挑戰
I gotta take the fight.
為什麼
Why?
那兩個混蛋殺了我爸
These dudes killed my pops.
結果現在還招搖過市胡說八道
Now they're parading around, talking shit?
我不能放過他們
I can't let that slide.
我是拳王對嗎
I'm the champ, right?
對
Yeah.
所以我別無選擇
So I ain't got a choice.
選擇嗎
Choice?
你爸爸當年也說過這句話
That's the same thing your father said,
然後我就眼睜睜看著他死在我懷裏
and he died right here, in my hands.
你看看他的選擇讓你媽媽受了多少苦
Look what his choice put your mother through.
你不想這種事落在比安卡頭上吧 孩子
You don't wanna really bring all that stuff up again, do you, kid?
我以為你能懂
I thought you would get it.
如果我不接受挑戰 我現在就得受著煎熬
If I don't take this fight, I gotta live with it right now.
那孩子是在仇恨裏長大的 你懂我的意思嗎
That kid was raised in hate, you know what I'm talking about?
而你不是 別去報仇
You weren't. Don't do it.
- 可你去了 - 那不一樣
- But you did. - It's different.
哪裏不一樣
It was different?
很多地方不一樣
It's a lot different.
其實那晚跟德拉戈對打的應該是我
I was supposed to be in there with Drago that night
而不是你爸爸
and not your father.
我本來可以扔毛巾認輸
And I could've thrown in the towel,
可我沒有
but I didn't.
我活該抱憾終身
And I gotta live with that.
後來我去找德拉戈報仇
And when I did get in that ring,
他的慾望摧毀了我的信念
that guy broke things in me
這輩子都無法復原
that ain't never been fixed.
這麼做不值
It's not worth it.
一點也不值
Not at all.
你為什麼想跟他打
Why do you wanna fight?
什麼意思 我剛剛都告訴你了
What are you talking about? I just told you why.
不 你沒有 多尼
No, you didn't, Donnie.
你到底為什麼想跟他打
Why do you wanna fight?
我知道他們為什麼跟你打
I get why they wanna fight you.
我知道他們父子想要什麼
I know what they're fighting for.
那你呢
What about you?
聽我說 你的人生什麼都輸不起
Listen to me, you got everything to lose.
而他沒什麼可輸的
He's got nothing to lose.
如果一個拳手沒什麼可輸的 那就太可怕了
When a fighter ain't got nothing to lose, he's dangerous.
我也不是吃素的
I'm dangerous!
你覺得我打不過他
You think I'm gonna lose.
我沒這麼說
I didn't say that.
你不是說過他沒什麼經驗嗎
Same guy that said he ain't have enough experience.
- 太嫩 對吧 - 對
- Raw, right? - Yeah.
可你還是覺得我打不過他
But you don't think I could beat him.
你是想說這個嗎
- Is that what you're trying to say? - No.
不 我想說的不是這個
No, that's not what I'm saying.
我是說我不可能永遠在這兒守著你
I'm saying I'm not gonna be here forever.
你這話是什麼意思
And what's that supposed to mean?
意思就是你得想清楚 別犯傻
That means you gotta do some smart thinking.
你覺得你守著我是犯傻嗎 洛奇
Oh, you wanna talk about smart decisions, Rock?
你孤零零住在這屋裏
You in this house all alone.
誰照顧你的 我
Who been taking care of you? Me.
我一直守著你
I've been here for you!
還有誰這麼對你
Who else you got?
聽著
Listen.
不管你支不支持 我都會應戰
I'm taking this fight with or without you.
我沒法支持你
It's gotta be without.
我做不到
I can't do it.
就這樣了嗎
So that's it?
你就這麼不管我了
You walkin' out on me?
這次你倒是不用糾結要不要再認輸了
At least you ain't gotta worry about throwing in the towel this time.
是啊
Yeah.
多尼 你還好嗎
D, are you okay?
洛奇那傢伙
Rocky, man.
洛奇怎麼了
Rocky what?
他拒絕幫我備戰
He ain't training me for the fight.
等等 你要接受挑戰嗎
Wait, you're taking the fight?
我們經歷了那麼多
All the shit that we've been through.
他說不管我就不管我了 簡直混蛋
He gonna leave me high and dry. That's bullshit!
他得癌癥都是我在照顧
I took care of him when he had cancer.
不然他早死了 比安
He could've been dead, B.
洛奇肯定有他的理由
I'm sure he has his reasons.
是嗎 什麼理由
Oh, yeah? Like what?
什麼理由
Like what?
我才不用他管
I don't need him.
我喜歡這裏
I love it.
我也是
Me, too.
我想在那間屋子辟一個小角落 佈置工作間
I want just a little piece of that room for a studio.
沒問題 隨便佈置
That works. It's all you.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
說不清可 能是一路飛過來有點累了
I don't know. Maybe I'm just a little tired from the flight.
沒事的
I'm okay.
那我們就別出去了
We don't have to go out.
不如待在家裏 叫個外賣
We can just stay in, order some food.
不 寶貝 你得見見你媽媽
Hmm. No, baby, you have to tell her.
你還在唱歌嗎
So, how's the music?
多尼沒告訴你嗎
Oh, Donnie didn't tell you?
多尼
D?
我忘了
Uh... I forgot.
忘了 我簽了公司
Oh. Yeah, I signed.
真的嗎
Hello.
真的 特別棒 公司也開始給我籌備發唱片了
Yeah, it's great. The record label really hit the ground running, too.
今年夏天我就要去音樂節演出了
I'm up for festivals this summer.
- 真是恭喜你 - 謝謝
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
洛奇怎麼樣了
So, how's Rocky?
他不想過來玩玩嗎
He didn't wanna make the trip?
媽 你也知道他這個人
Nah, Ma, you know how he is
他不愛出遠門
with the traveling.
好吧 媽
Okay, Ma.
你肯定已經猜到了 不過
I'm sure you already guessed it, but...
沒錯
Oh, yeah.
我早就猜到了
I already know.
這麼愛吃咸的
All the salt,
頭髮也亮
shiny hair,
簡直容光煥發
glowing skin.
懷孕幾個月了
How far along are you?
媽 你是以為
Ma, you think...
你以為
You think...
不是
No.
我們都還沒 不是的 這真是
We couldn't even... No.
媽喜歡開玩笑
Your mamma's got jokes, okay.
不 我沒懷孕
No, I'm not.
好吧
All right.
- 結果是什麼 - 多尼 別碰
- What's it say? - D, don't touch it.
我又不在乎它上面有沒有尿 我只想看看
No, I don't care if you peed on it. I just want to see...
我是讓你別亂動它
I don't want you to mess it up.
怎麼樣
What's it say?
有兩條藍線
It's two blue lines.
兩條藍線 是什麼意思
Two blue lines? What does that mean?
兩條藍線
Two blue lines.
老天 它可能是壞了
Maybe it's broke.
這不可能
That's crazy.
我很猶豫 多尼
Hell, I don't know, D.
寶貝 我很猶豫
Baby, I don't know.
你一直都想要孩子 對吧
You did say you always wanted kids, right?
對 可我沒想這麼早要
Yeah, but I didn't say so soon.
我不知道我..我們
I don't know if I'm...
準備好了嗎
If we are ready.
現在準備也不遲
Let's get ready, then.
對
Yeah.
她告訴家裏人了嗎
Did she tell her family yet?
她現在就和她姑媽打電話呢
She's, uh, on the phone with her aunt right now.
比安卡可是好姑娘
Oh, that Bianca's a good one.
她怎麼會答應嫁給你呢 我是真想不通
Why she agreed to marry you, I do not know.
其實我也想不通
I don't know either.
你們回來可真好
Oh, it's good to have you home.
媽
Ma, um...
那場比賽
That fight
你知道
between me
對手是伊凡·德拉戈的兒子
and Ivan Drago's son...
我想接受挑戰
I'm gonna take it.
好吧
Okay.
就這樣嗎
That's it?
那你還想聽我說什麼
What else is there to say?
難道你不擔心嗎
So, that doesn't bother you?
我怎麼可能不擔心
Oh, you think this doesn't bother me?
可你是成年人
You're a grown man.
我和別人怎麼想對你來說都不重要
It doesn't matter what I or anyone else thinks.
你想跟那個人打是你的事情
You wanna fight this man, that's your business.
你又不需要我祝福你
You don't need my blessings.
洛奇不也沒祝福你嗎
You clearly don't have Rocky's.
洛奇理解不了
Rocky don't get it.
死的不是他爸
It wasn't his dad.
我的人生都改寫了
It changed my life.
還有你的人生
Your life.
你難道不想爸爸嗎
You're telling me you don't miss him?
你說什麼
Excuse me!
別把這事扯到我頭上
Do not try to make this about me.
也別拿你爸爸給自己當借口
And don't pretend that it's about your father.
沒有你爸 你也成了世界拳王
You became the world champion without him.
可我好像不想當拳王
Then why don't I feel like it?
要是你爸還活著 他也會告訴你 他不想當拳王
If your father was here, he would tell you he didn't feel like it either.
可他不在了
But he's not.
我只希望你能陪自己的孩子成長
I just hope you'll be here for your child.
你怎麼這麼傻
Why are you so stupid?
別鬧
Stop.
多尼 你那兩撮鬍渣撓得我癢癢
D, you're tickling me with that fake beard.
敢這麼說我鬍子
The disrespect.
給我和寶寶唱首歌
Why don't you sing for us?
不 我可不是你的點唱機
No, I am not your jukebox.
也別指望我光著腳 挺著大肚子
I'm not gonna be walking around here, barefoot and pregnant,
還給你做什麼三明治吃
making you sandwiches either.
你聽聽 不給做三明治 也不給唱歌
Did you hear that? No sandwiches, no singing.
你媽媽對咱倆真狠心
Your mamma just hating on us.
你聽見了嗎
Did you hear that?
要是寶寶隨我怎麼辦
What if the baby can't, D?
什麼隨你
Can't what?
失聰
Can't hear.
你知道這病可能遺傳吧
You know it can be hereditary, right?
一切都會好起來的
Everything is gonna be fine.
我保證
I promise.
便利店 寵物超市
德爾斐拳擊學院
這場比賽的關注度一定非常高
People are gonna be all over this fight.
你們背後可是血海深仇啊 老弟
It got a lot of bad history, man.
糾葛太多
Everything.
你老爸
Your dad.
還有你爸啊
And yours, too.
你爸當過我爸的教練
Don't forget that he trained him.
我明白你之前為什麼不教我了
I know why you didn't train me before.
我當時不夠格
I wasn't ready.
維克托夠格
You was right.
是 可這次不一樣
Yeah, but this is different.
德拉戈的兒子
Drago's kid...
塊頭大
Big.
速度快
Fast.
很強壯
Strong.
路子還野得很
Unorthodox.
他是個怪物 小子
He's a monster, boy.
這個人身上就沒有短板
It's a balanced breakfast over there.
你覺得你對付得了嗎
You think you ready for all that?
我必須對付他
I gotta be.
你不願意幫我沒關係
But if you ain't gonna do it for me,
就當是為他們
at least do it for them.
好好考慮一下
Think about it.
就當替他們了卻遺憾
Beat what they couldn't beat.
也能洗刷平反他們的名聲
Change the way they were remembered.
抓住這個機會 我們就能改寫歷史
This is our chance to rewrite history.
我們的歷史
Our history.
他的戰績也許不怎麼樣 但是相信我
His record might be light, but, believe me,
他絕對不好對付
he ain't no undercard.
你一定得聽我的
So, you gotta be with me.
都聽你的
I'm right here.
試試吧
We'll see.
奎迪對戰德拉戈
Creed versus Drago.
這場決鬥有特殊的意義
That means something.
你決定應戰是因為你們兩家的歷史淵源嗎
Did that factor into your decision to take this fight?
提到奎迪就不得不說德拉戈 對吧
I mean, you can't say Creed without Drago, right?
家庭影院體育頻道
你們想看我們打
This is what y'all want.
大家都想看我們打
It's what everyone wants.
還有件事很難不注意到
Also, can't help but to notice,
那就是這次你的團隊裏缺了一個人
who won't be in your corner this time around.
洛奇在享受天倫之樂
Rocky's taking some family time.
我還有小公爵
But Duke's got me.
他父親把畢生絕技都傳給我爸爸了
His father taught my father everything he knows.
快 多尼 速度才是關鍵
Speed, D. That's how we gonna beat him.
注重技巧 加強速度
Technique, speed...
我相信他能幫我做好備戰
I'm confident he'll have me ready for this fight.
那想到你父親和德拉戈當年的仇恨與糾葛
And knowing what happened between your father and Drago,
想必你也有一些擔心吧
you must have some worry.
我有什麼可擔心的
What would I be afraid of?
誰想嘗嘗我的厲害 我是拳手 就得打拳 對嗎
I'm a fighter. This is what I do, right?
誰是拳王
Who the champ?
這就是我
It's who I am.
看起來不錯
Looking good!
阿多尼斯·奎迪對戰維托·德拉龍
奎迪
Creed! Creed! Creed!
阿多尼斯·奎迪對戰維克托·德拉龍
你可比你爸矮小多了
You're much smaller than your father.
你敢提我爸
Don't you talk about my pop.
你想現在打也可以
Hey, we could do this right here, bro.
- 上來啊 - 多尼
- Step up here! - D!
你爸明天就幫不了你了
He can't help you no more!
聽見了嗎 你能躲在在台下了
You hear me? He can't help behind that ring!
你站在拳台上也就能耍耍嘴皮子了
You stand there. All you're doing is talking, homie.
你爸保護不了你了 懂嗎
Your pops can't protect you, you feel me?
你們不准提我爸 你們有膽就別走
Don't talk about my father! Don't turn your back on me!
這是我的主場 老兄
You in my house, homie!
艾德裏安餐廳
阿多尼斯·奎迪對戰維克托·德拉龍 今晚直播
一定要攔住他們 我們在更衣室
Make sure they hold them down. We're in the dressing room.
我是吉姆·蘭普利 我旁邊是羅伊·瓊斯
Jim Lampley here, along with Roy Jones.
今晚的大戰馬上就要拉開帷幕了
We're moments away from tonight's main event.
吉姆 我真的做夢也想不到
Jim, I would have never thought in a million years
我們竟然能看到奎迪家和德拉戈家下一代的對戰
I'd witness another Creed versus Drago fight.
是 好戲開演了 羅伊 小德拉戈正向拳台走來
Well, get ready, Roy. Drago makes his way to the ring.
他的父親正帶著他 穿過敵意洶涌的人潮
His father leads the way through the hostile crowd.
這是民心所向的力量 奎迪肯定也感覺到了
You can feel the energy. I'm sure Creed does.
觀眾們都支持他
He has a big advantage with the fans in his corner.
巴克萊中心體育場
集中精神 這是你的主場 兄弟 一定不能分心
Stay focused. You're at home, baby. Focus is the key.
考慮到德拉戈的體格和打鬥風格
Given Drago's size and style,
他可能會用力量來壓制奎迪的速度
he'll look to use his power to counter Creed's speed.
你知道我們都支持你
Remember why we're here, man.
我是拳王
I'm the champ.
阿多尼斯·奎迪今晚的閃亮登場引發了全場矚目
Adonis Creed making a grand entrance tonight.
這點像他的父親 奎迪家的人都很張揚
Like his father, Creed is ever the showman,
能讓觀眾為他們瘋狂
and is energizing the crowd.
奎迪是想讓德拉戈看看 誰才是這拳台的主宰
Creed is letting Drago know exactly who this arena belongs to.
這一切就彷彿是莎士比亞筆下的情節
It all feels so Shakespearean.
兩位男孩 出身可謂是雲泥之別 卻被一樁悲情的往事綁在了一起
Two sons, raised a world apart, yet inexorably linked by tragedy.
世界拳擊理事會
好了 先生們
Now, gentlemen,
我在更衣室已經重申過比賽規則了
I went over the rules in the dressing room.
我要提醒兩位 需時刻遵守規則 公平競賽
I wanna caution you to keep this fight clean at all times.
也需時刻保護好人身安全
Protect yourself at all times.
請兩位務必聽從我說的話
And what I say, you must obey.
祝你們好運 碰拳套吧
Good luck. Touch gloves.
請碰拳套
Touch gloves.
奎迪的教練洛奇·巴爾博亞並未前來觀戰
Creed fights without longtime trainer Rocky Balboa.
小公爵如何指導奎迪摒棄世仇的影響
Interesting to see how Duke manages the corner
好好發揮 將是一大看點
with so much bad blood between the fighters.
看著他
Look at him.
想像他徑直朝你衝過來
He think he gonna run straight through you.
- 給他點顏色看看 好嗎 - 好
- You show him what's up. - Yeah.
這是你的主場 懂嗎
This is your house, all right?
- 這是我的主場 - 上吧 兄弟
- It's my house. - Let's go, baby.
開始
Box!
比賽正式開始了
And we're underway.
單從競技狀態上來看
If all goes according to form,
奎迪被公認是靈活的全能型拳手
Creed is seen as the more versatile boxer, quicker...
對 用刺拳 逼出破綻
Yeah, baby, throw that jab! Let it rip!
德拉戈 現在也要開始發力了
Drago is trying to land something big.
重錘 重錘
Dig, dig.
攻擊下盤
Downstairs.
奎迪連續出拳擊中對方身體
Creed connects with a couple of body shots.
奎迪向上揮出一記右勾拳
And a right hand upstairs for Creed.
德拉戈按兵不動 還未發動有效攻擊
Drago hasn't thrown a meaningful punch yet.
奎迪又是一記右勾拳
And another right hand for Creed.
奎迪擋住了這一拳
Creed blocked that punch
不過他還是被逼到了場邊
and still it knocked him back into the ropes.
有兩下子
Yeah, we good.
奎迪有點生氣了 吉姆
Creed doesn't like that, Jim.
別被騙了 小子 他是想激怒你
Don't be stupid, kid. He's baiting you.
奎迪步步緊逼 帶著怒氣發起了猛攻
Creed pressing now, angrily rushes forward with a volley of punches.
他要你近身
He's pulling you in.
德拉戈這記左勾拳真是穩准狠
A huge left hook by Drago!
- 奎迪似乎被這一拳打懵了 - 加油
- Come on, kid. - Creed shaken up by that punch.
別有雜念
Clear your head.
奎迪佔據了拳台中央
Creed commands the center of the ring,
卻被狼狽地狠狠打中了左肋
but there's a hard body shot to the ribs.
現在右側也受到了重擊
And another one on the other side.
你怎麼了 兄弟 振作點 多尼
What you doing, baby? What you doing, D?
德拉戈揮出一記右勾拳 打得奎迪仰過頭去
And a right hand by Drago that knocks Creed's head back.
奎迪感受到了對手拳頭的力量
Creed can feel the power behind those punches.
現在德拉戈始正式反擊了
And now Drago is on the attack.
出拳 舉起拳頭 繼續
Jab out, jab out, jab out. Hands up, let's go!
德拉戈沿著圍繩步步為營
Drago's stalking him along the ropes.
別靠近圍繩 多尼
Get off the ropes, D!
別進角落
Out the corner!
不 多尼 離開角落
No, D! Out the corner, out the corner!
德拉戈猛地揮出右拳 奎迪被打都站不穩了
Hard right hand by Drago, and Creed is shaken
至此比賽的第一回合結束
as the first round comes to a close.
許多不在現場觀賽的觀眾 可能會有點驚訝
I think most watching at home are a little surprised
因為維克托·德拉戈
by how impressive Viktor Drago has looked
在剛開場的這幾分鐘裏表現得相當令人驚艷
in these opening minutes of the fight.
兩位拳手積怨已久
With the history these men share,
小公爵光是要讓奎迪免受情緒干擾
Duke may have his hands full keeping Creed
恐怕就已經費盡心力了
from letting his emotions get the best of him.
怎麼回事 多尼
What you doing, D?
- 你得按照咱們的計劃來 - 我知道
- You need to stick with the game plan. - I know, I know.
別靠近圍繩 調整角度 你沒掌握好角度
Stay off the line. Take your angles. You ain't taking your angles.
我知道
I know!
如果他對你出左勾拳 就得小心
If he throws you a left hook...
你再這樣擋他啊
Come on, man, hold the phone on that.
- 怎麼擋我會不知道 - 既然你知道
- You think I don't know that shit? - Well, if you know it,
那就擋啊
do it!
他害怕了
我能看出來
那你告訴我
為什麼你還沒打敗他
把他幹掉
現在第二回合即將開始 觀眾席上還是一片沸騰
And now, as we prepare for round two, this crowd is still buzzing
在第一回合的對決中 德拉戈揮舞的重拳之下是深沉的敵意
from the vicious rally that Drago brought forth in the last minute
他發起的連續攻擊 竟然在最後一刻
of round number one.
清醒點 別犯傻
Come out smart.
將奎迪打得全無招架之力
Got Creed in serious trouble as the round came to a close.
開始
Box!
現在第二回合開始了
And now, round two begins.
德拉戈一上來就發動了猛烈進攻 絲毫沒有遲疑
And Drago comes out throwing, wasting no time.
- 別靠近圍繩 - 奎迪又被逼退到場邊
- Get off the ropes! - And Creed is backed
他試圖躲開對方的強力攻擊
into the ropes, trying to avoid those power shots.
該死
Damn.
場上局勢迅速進入白熱化
Things just got ugly fast.
德拉戈又是一記強勁的右勾拳 奎迪現在真有大麻煩了
And another hard right hand shot, and Creed is in big trouble now.
腳下別停 多尼
Keep moving, Donnie.
這一記右勾拳打得奎迪雙腿發軟
A massive right hand sends Creed reeling.
他在重新調整步調
He tries to regain his footing.
再次試圖回擊
Creed trying to answer back.
又一記結實的勾拳 打得奎迪翻出了圍繩
And now a huge hook sends Creed flying through the ropes!
挺住
Come on, kid.
二
Two!
三
Three!
四
Four!
五 六
Five! Six!
很好
That's it, that's it, that's it.
奎迪 奎迪
Creed! Creed!
- 你還好嗎 - 還好
- You okay? - Yeah.
開始
Box!
現在奎迪必須找到
Creed needs something
扭轉戰局的辦法
to try to turn this fight around.
把他幹掉
德拉戈的重拳持續來襲
Drago just keeps coming.
奎迪左肋又受到重擊
What a big rib shot!
糟了
Shit.
連續兩記右勾拳挾雷霆之力 打在奎通的胸腔 這沉重的悶響
Those were two tremendous right hands to the rib cage.
都能傳到最後一排觀眾的耳朵裏
You could've heard that one in the nosebleed seats.
奎迪的痛苦顯而易見 但他還是盡力爬了起來
Creed clearly in pain, as he finds a way to his feet.
他並不打算放棄
Not ready to give up yet.
可怎麼說呢 情況不妙啊 吉姆
I don't know. This is getting dangerous, Jim.
你還好嗎 靠近我
Okay! Come to me!
拜利斯裁判讓雙方繼續比賽
And now, Bayless is gonna let him go again.
準備好
Ready?
開始
Box!
奎迪掙扎著離開角落
He comes barreling out of the corner.
一記右勾拳
Huge right hook!
德拉戈想速戰速決
Drago trying to end it.
奎迪在結束鈴響之前終於又揮出一拳
And Creed delivers a big right hand at the bell.
退後 退到角落裏去
Get back! Get back to your corner!
拜利斯攔住了德拉戈 德拉戈好像有點受挫
Bayless restraining Drago, seemingly frustrated...
聽我指揮
Obey my commands.
畢竟差一點就結束這一回合了
...as he was close to finishing the fight.
你得趕緊拿出本事來 不然我就得叫停比賽了
You got to show me something. If not, I'm gonna stop it.
你還能打嗎
Can you fight?
我能打 能打
Oh, I'm good, I'm good.
你不能打了 我去叫停比賽
Hell no. I'm calling this fight.
兄弟 不要叫停
Nigga, don't call this shit.
兄弟 沒必要求別人認同你
You ain't got to prove shit to nobody.
你看看你 肋骨可能都斷了
Look at you. Your ribs look like they broke.
別叫停比賽
You can't call this fight.
他讓你成了個笑話
這就是為什麼這些人都看不起我們
這也是你媽拋棄我們的原因
就是這樣
把我的護齒拿來
Hand me my mouthpiece.
把護齒拿來
My mouthpiece.
別打了
Don't do it.
進入第三回合
Now, as we go to round three,
阿多尼斯·奎斯已經被打得精疲力盡 身受重傷
Adonis Creed has been beaten up and bloodied
德拉戈連續不斷的重拳出擊
by an avalanche of power shots
在前兩個回合讓他吃盡了苦頭
from Viktor Drago in the first two rounds.
我們看看阿多尼斯·奎迪還剩多少能耐
And we'll see how much Adonis Creed has left now,
他掙扎著想活下去 繼續戰鬥
as he tries to stay alive in the fight.
不要再打了
Stop the fight.
德拉戈強悍的臂膀虎虎生威
Dangerous swings from Drago
奎迪正在拚命抵擋對方的攻擊
as Creed desperately tries to hold him off.
德拉戈繼續對奎迪的身體發動猛烈攻擊
Drago's still putting huge pressure on the body.
搞什麼 快還擊啊
Come on, stop the fight!
德拉戈又揮出一記重拳
And another shot by Drago!
奎迪似乎已經撐不住了
Creed seemingly on his last legs!
可德拉戈未曾停手 反擊 多尼
- Drago on the attack. - Come on, D!
奎迪的胸腔受到了致命的一擊
Oh, and with a devastating shot to the rib cage.
停止比賽
Stop! Stop!
德拉戈應該被取消資格 至少看起來是這樣
This is an obvious disqualification, or so it would appear
因為他最後揮出那一拳時
because Creed was fully down
奎迪已經倒地毫無還手之力了
at the moment that Drago landed that last shot.
- 不 - 你這是要殺人麼
- No! - You wanna kill somebody?
- 不行 不行 - 冷靜點
- No way, baby. No! - Easy, easy!
- 不不不 - 別急
- No. No, no, no! - Come on.
冷靜點
No! Just relax.
整個體育場都陷入了沉默
This arena is completely silent
觀眾們都在等待
as the audience waits to see
醫護人員會為年輕的阿多尼斯·奎迪 診斷出怎樣的傷勢
what will be the condition of young Adonis Creed.
除了眼眶骨破裂 還斷了兩根肋骨 腦震盪程度三級
Cracked orbital bone, two cracked ribs, grade-3 concussion,
腎臟破裂 以及多處挫傷
ruptured kidney, numerous contusions.
腎臟破裂會不會...
A ruptured kidney, is that--
這些傷好好修養都能痊癒
His injuries will heal with rest and time,
包括腎臟
including the kidney.
現在來看沒必要動手術
Now, we shouldn't have to resort to surgery,
不過得留院觀察至少48小時 以防傷勢惡化
but we will need to keep him here for at least 48 hours, as a precaution.
還有 他現在麻醉勁兒還沒過去 不過再過一會兒肯定會醒的
Now he's still numb from the morphine, but he'll certainly feel it later.
- 好的 - 你還好嗎
- Okay. - You okay?
還好 我坐一會兒就行
Fine, I just gotta sit.
要是你感覺不對
If you're expecting...
不 我沒事
No, I'm fine.
不 我說真的 別太擔心 好嗎
No, no, seriously. Take it easy, okay?
打擾一下 尤厄爾醫生
Excuse me, Dr. Ewell.
有人找你 這邊請
You have a visitor. Right this way.
比安卡
Bianca.
我很抱歉事情變成這樣
Listen, I'm so sorry everything went...
我就該守著他
I should've been there.
真的對不起
I'm so sorry.
真的
I am.
我也很懊悔
Me, too.
我能看看他嗎
Is it okay if I see him?
對我們來說有區別嗎 現場情況大家都看到了
What difference do it make to us? We saw what happened.
裁判和組委會公正裁決就行
They doing what they supposed to be doing.
這我不管
I don't care.
對
Right. Okay.
好 知道了
Got it.
理事會不打算對裁判的裁決提出異議
WBC's not gonna contest the referee's decision,
所以維克托維持判罰
so Viktor remains disqualified.
取消比賽資格
Bottom line,
但至少你保住了拳王之名
you still the champ.
好了 我不打擾你休息了
I'm gonna let you rest, man.
你要是有事就叫我 我就在外面
So, if you need something, you know, I'm outside.
有人來看你 多尼
Got some company, D.
遠鑒字幕組製作
[Visionary] 0day-sub
你做得很好
You did good.
我們盡力了
We tried.
知道嗎 你的比賽我在費城看了
You know, I watched you back in Philadelphia.
你真的非常堅強 沒人能質疑你這點
You showed a ton of heart. I mean, there's no doubt about it.
熱門電影字幕歡迎關注微博 @遠鑒字幕組v
字幕組官方公眾號：禾寫電影
若是想施展您的翻譯才華 讓自己的名字出現在字幕開頭
遠鑒字幕組歡迎您加入
遠鑒字幕組招新群 483552098
招募英語翻譯 誠邀您的加入
- 你真的很堅強 - 堅強嗎
- Showed a ton of heart. - Heart?
我不要這種狗屁安慰
Man, I ain't trying to hear that shit.
多尼 別這麼對洛奇
D. It's Rock.
觀眾您好
如果給您分發的資源的人未明確指出是遠鑒字幕組作品
或是裁剪\去除掉了片頭的字幕組製作人信息
說明您可能獲取的是二手資源
沒關係
Oh, it's okay. It's all right.
獲取一手資源 拒絕二手資源 從您做起
更多精彩內容 敬請關注微博 @遠鑒字幕組v
不行 你們倆不能這麼說話
No, you guys gotta work it out.
這場比賽我根本必輸無疑 對嗎
I lost the fight before it even started, right?
不 不是
No. No, no.
不是 那傢伙個頭那麼大 太壯了
This guy was... He's a big guy, he's strong.
臂展又比你長 什麼條件都很好
He got the reach on you. He got all kinds of--
你又想指導我了嗎
Oh, now you're trying to train me?
想給我當教練嗎
Be my coach?
你看看我
No, look at me.
看看我
Look at me.
你還跑過來幹什麼
What are you still doing here?
你來收拾我的爛攤子嗎
Here to pick up the pieces?
不是
No.
幹嗎不待在費城
Shouldn't you be in Philly?
- 阿多尼斯 - 不 沒關係
- Adonis. - No, it's okay.
我不想讓他難受
I don't want him to get all...
你們好好互相照顧
Take care of each other.
對不起
I'm sorry.
好了 寶貝
Baby.
他是愛你的 多尼
He loves you, D.
看看我
Look at me.
我一直在看著你 寶貝
I'm looking right at you, babe.
我們的孩子會怎麼看我
How's that baby gonna look at me?
電梯
阿多尼斯 你真覺得自己是拳王嗎
Adonis, do you really feel like a champ?
你覺得你配得起金腰帶嗎
Do you think you deserve to keep the belt?
你那不叫贏 阿多尼斯
Why would you take that fight, Adonis?
阿多尼斯·奎迪就這水平嗎
Is this it for Adonis Creed?
沒事
I'm cool. I'm cool.
- 親愛的 讓我幫你吧 - 我說了 我能走
- D, please, let me help you, baby. - I said I can walk.
求你坐下吧 我說了 我能行
- Please sit-- - I said I got it.
我說不好
I don't know. Lately, it's like...
他最近好像跟以前不一樣了
He hasn't really been himself.
我理解
And I get it.
畢竟他很受煎熬
'Cause he's going through a lot.
他剛剛開始接受物理治療
He's just starting physical therapy.
在盡力恢復健康
Trying to get himself right.
但是
And
他有點
he's, uh...
冷漠
distant
而且 非常游離
and disconnected.
好像現在對他來說什麼都不重要
It's like nothing really matters to him right now.
包括我他也不放在心上
Including me.
這不像他
Which is new.
對
Yeah.
聽著 你得陪著他 好好照顧他
Listen, be there for him, take care of him,
付出你的愛
give him your love.
不過你也得明白
But also, you gotta realize he's in a place right now
他現在這個狀態只有靠他自己才能解脫出來
that only he can get himself out of.
可他正在經受的這有一切
And with everything he's going through--
你管他正在經受什麼呢
With everything he's going through?
他這一路上每步都有你的支持
You've been in his corner every step of the way.
可他是個成熟男人了
He's a grown man.
他需要自己從內而外的痊癒
He's gotta heal from the inside out.
相信我 我懂 我經歷過
Trust me, I know. I've been there.
感覺到了嗎
Feel her?
是
Yeah.
德拉戈的精彩表現讓所有質疑都煙消雲散
Highlights of Drago silencing critics tonight
第一回合就勢如破竹 將安東尼·諾瓦克擊倒出局
with a devastating first round knockout of Anthony Novak.
接下來馬克斯·凱勒曼將進行賽後採訪
Here's a post-fight interview with Max Kellerman.
維克托 距離你輸給阿多尼斯·奎迪
Viktor, here we are just months
那場有爭議的比賽 已經好幾個月了
since your controversial loss to Adonis Creed.
這次能贏感覺如何
How does this win feel?
我輸過嗎
What loss?
抱歉 我說的是
Excuse me.
你對戰阿多尼斯·奎迪卻被取消資格的事
From your disqualification to Adonis Creed.
好在你今晚贏了 感覺怎麼樣
But how does this feel to you tonight?
沒什麼感覺 我要再跟奎迪打
I don't care. Creed must fight me.
如果他不跟你打呢
And if he doesn't fight you?
那他就不算拳王
Then he's no champion.
你聽到了嗎 阿多尼斯 對方已經下了戰書了
There you have it, Adonis. Challenge is on the table.
我們非常為你驕傲
敬你 維克托
敬你們
願你的成功 能重現俄羅斯拳壇昔日的輝煌
你是我們的希望
維克托
請收下這份禮物
德拉戈
現在你們要做的
就是趁這一次比賽一舉奪下金腰帶 懂嗎
坐吧
你好 維克托
相信你一定覺得非常自豪吧
維克托
Viktor!
裏面那些人是為了我們專程到這兒來的
- 為了你來的 - 裏面那些人嗎
裏面那些人怎麼對你的 他們當年把你趕走了
- 我們為什麼非要到這裏來 - 這是為了將來
我根本都不算認識那個女人
我也巴不得不認識他
維克托
她當年拋棄了你
他們都是
那些人都把你給拋棄了
他們還羞辱你
是我輸了比賽
我當年輸了比賽
但你不會再輸下去了
德爾斐拳擊學院
車不錯
What's good?
好好保養 好久不見 忙什麼呢
Just maintaining, man. Long time no see, what's up?
也沒什麼事 就是瞎忙 裝修 待產
Nothing, man. Just been caught up. You know, the house, the baby.
你知道多麻煩
You know how it is.
好吧 比安卡好嗎
Yeah? How Bianca doing?
她挺好 挺好
She's good. She's good.
好
Good, good, good.
其實我一直很想聯繫你 兄弟
Listen, man, I've been meaning to hit you up, though.
理事會想知道我們下一場比賽跟誰打
Commissioner wanna know who we plan to fight next.
就算不跟德拉戈打
You ain't gotta fight Drago,
你也得跟別人打
but you gotta fight someone.
你得守住金腰帶
You gotta defend the belt.
不然它就要被收回去了
Otherwise, it's gonna be vacated.
你知道 我能幫你 選個好打一點的對手
I could set up a little, you know, tune-up fight, kind of.
算了 這樣吧
No. You know what, man?
你現在還是別操心這些事了
Don't worry about none of that right now.
就進來玩會兒吧
Listen, just come on inside.
打打沙包 熱熱身
Hit the bag, man, warm up.
好
Yeah.
我先去拿裝備 然後再進去找你
Yeah, I'm gonna grab my stuff, and I'm gonna meet you in there.
好吧 兄弟
All right, man.
用全身的重量出拳
Put your body weight into that glove.
這就對了 上前一步
There you go. Lean in it.
是啊 我都給你打了無數個電話了
Yeah, I called you, like, a thousand times.
是 我家燈壞了
Yeah, it's about the light.
壞了多久嗎
How long?
仔細算算 有好幾年了吧
You want to be specific? Couple years.
對
Yeah.
只是擰個燈泡而已 用得了幾個人
I mean, how many guys does it take to screw in a light bulb?
我可沒開玩笑
I'm not joking.
瑪麗·安·奎迪寄  洛奇·巴爾博亞 收
我再打給你們好嗎
Can I call you guys back?
行
Yeah.
他仍然需要你 瑪麗·安
媽
Hey, Ma.
Ma.
媽媽
Hey, Ma.
最近好嗎 小子
How you doing, kid?
你過來幹什麼
What are you doing here?
希望你別介意
I hope you don't mind,
是你媽媽請我過來的 因為她非常擔心你
your mom asked if I would come out 'cause she's worried about you.
我也是
I am, too.
我很好
I'm good.
你不用大老遠過來一趟
You didn't have to come all this way.
我坐火車來的
By train.
在車上待了三天
Three days on a train.
也挺好 你知道 我有思考的時間了
It's all right, you know, gives you time to think.
可以看著風景 像明信片一樣從窗外閃過
And you watch all these places whipping by the windows like postcards.
也是一種不錯的經歷
It's quite an experience.
是 你開心就好
Yeah, I mean, if you say so.
是 真挺好
Yeah, it was nice.
這個房間太棒了
This is wonderful.
這兒怎麼能有這麼多的獎盃呢
How you have all this out here.
你也能有這麼多獎盃
You could have the same.
是嗎 我可沒有自信
Yeah, I wouldn't say that.
我說的不只是榮譽
I mean, not just the shiny stuff,
有些東西更有價值
but the better stuff.
比如更好的人生
Have a better life.
做更好的人
Be a better man.
知道嗎 我其實一直在想你之前質問我說
You know, I was thinking about what you were saying about
我是不是覺得留在原地守著你就是在犯傻
what smart decisions have I made lately.
但沒想出個結果
Couldn't think of many.
跟你說我兒子的兒子
You know, I wasn't even there when my son's son,
就是我的親孫子
my grandson,
他出生時 我沒去
was born.
他現在可能都已經長這麼高了
I mean, he's like that tall now probably.
我卻還不認識他 他也不認識我
I don't even know him. He doesn't know me.
真的很可悲
It's pathetic.
那幹嗎不給他
Well, why won't you just
打電話
call him?
沒那麼容易 你懂嗎
It ain't that easy, you know...
聽著
Listen,
我不希望你重蹈覆轍 犯我犯過的錯
I don't want you making the same mistakes I made.
你懂我意思嗎
You know what I mean?
所以你要問問你自己
So, you gotta ask yourself,
到底什麼東西才是有價值的
what's the valuable stuff?
我以前也問過你類似的問題
It's like I asked you before.
你一路奮戰到底是為了什麼
What were you really fighting for?
我之前很怕
I was afraid.
榮譽
Of this.
怕達不到別人的期望
Expectations.
怕當拳王
Being the champ.
我怕我自己達不到爸爸的高度
I was scared I couldn't do what he couldn't.
挺奇怪的
It's weird.
我曾覺得他是我的一部分
I used to feel like he was apart of me.
現在我卻聽不到他的召喚了
Now I can't hear him, or that thing,
我聽不到他讓我上拳台奮戰
that thing that tells me to get in the ring.
要腳下不停 一直舉著拳頭
Move my feet, keep my hands up.
打倒所有阻擋我的東西
Hit anything that gets in my way.
我再也聽不到了
I can't hear it anymore.
我都不知道我怎麼輸的
I don't even know how I lost.
你這麼想就不對
Your mind wasn't right.
其實你天生就不適合走你爸爸這樣傳奇的路線
And your natural style just won't work with a guy that big.
那我更適合你的路線嗎
You saying yours was better?
我贏過 不是嗎
I won, didn't I?
- 見到你真好 - 我也很開心見到你
- Good seeing you, Unc. - Great to see you, too.
我之前跟你媽媽仔細聊過一陣 她說
I was talking with your mother,
你給你的孩子起了個名字叫做
and she says you came up with this name for the child.
- 阿瑪拉 - 阿瑪拉
- Amara. - Amara.
- 是 - 好
- Yeah. - Yeah.
有什麼問題嗎
Why, what's wrong with that?
不 沒事 這名字很好聽 就是有點不好念
No, it's a beautiful name, but it's kind of complicated.
為什麼不起一個能讓人
Why don't you think about something,
至少能讓我念得順口點的
at least I would, a little simpler to say,
比如貝姬或者凱特之類的
like "Becky" or "Cate," something like that.
凱特·奎迪
Cate Creed?
凱特·奎迪 雙C開頭 挺好記
Cate Creed. Two "C's." Easy to remember.
你知道黑人不起這種名字吧
You do know she's gonna be black, right?
對啊 我給忘了
Oh, that's right, I forgot.
好吧
Okay.
- 喂 媽 - 好吧
- Hey, Ma. - Yeah.
等等 現在嗎
Wait, right now?
- 放鬆點 - 好的
- Relax. - Okay.
什麼事都不會有
- Everything's gonna be fine. - Mmm-hmm.
你就是到這裏來陪她的 懂嗎 你就做這個
You just gotta be there for her, okay? That's your job.
我明白
I got you, I got you.
你記好
- And remember-- - Yeah.
你這輩子的巔峰時刻就是今天 就是在這兒
Today is gonna be the best day of your life. Right here.
- 懂嗎 - 懂
- All right? - Yeah.
這是你的人生巔峰
Best day of your life.
- 我要有孩子了 - 我感覺跟我有孩子了似的
- I'm having a baby. - I feel like I'm having a baby.
兒子
- Boy! - Hey.
- 你怎麼這麼晚 - 我知道
- What you doing? - I know--
不 這沒關係 趕緊到裏面去吧
No, never mind. Just get in here.
好
Okay. Okay, okay.
我說過 你需要我 我一直在的
Like I said, I'll be here if you need me.
- 好的 - 好
- All right. - All right.
我會盡力去幫他
You know, I'm gonna do what I can.
你能趕過來 就已經幫他太多了
You being here is more than enough.
謝謝
Thank you.
羅伯特 604-555-0117
巴爾博亞先生
Mr. Balboa?
孩子生了
- Mmm. - She's here.
那太好了
Oh, that's great.
真是天大的好消息
That's absolutely good.
真的是棒極了
That's fantastic.
大叔 跟你的教女打個招呼
Hey, Unc, say hi to your goddaughter.
讓我做教父真榮幸
Wow. That's quite an honor.
- 讓我看看你 - 你看看
- Let me see you. - Here she is.
你好啊 小美人
Hey, hello, beautiful.
對了 護士
So, nurse...
檢查什麼時候做
...what about the test?
你們先別急
Relax for now.
聽性腦幹反應的檢查 等比安卡和阿瑪拉都休息好了就會安排人
We'll run an auditory exam as soon as you and Amara get some rest.
沒關係 寶貝
It's okay, babe.
幸好她長得像你
Thank God she looks like you.
可不是嗎
Yeah, right.
這檢查會不會讓她不舒服
So, is she gonna feel anything?
不會 這是無痛檢查 保證不疼
No, it's painless. I promise.
好了 人都就位了
Okay. Now that they're in place,
現在我們要做的就是 給她一些短促的聲音刺激
what we're gonna do is give her a series of click stimuli
音量大概有三十五分貝
around 35 decibels
以檢查她的神經系統反應
and check her neural responses.
聲音大不大
Is that loud?
在正常音頻範圍內
Normal auditory range.
好了
Okay.
那就開始
Here we go.
阿瑪拉·奎迪 聽性腦幹反應測試
我們具體要看什麼
So what exactly are we looking for?
讀數 看棘波
A reading. Spikes.
好吧 目前看不到有任何棘波之類的波形
So, we're not seeing any waves or spikes, uh,
因為孩子有家族病史擔心也是很正常的
and given your family history, there is some cause for concern.
不過現在下結論太早
However, it is very early...
醫生說還得做檢查
They're gonna run some more tests.
下結論太早了 有時候也會有誤診的
They said it's early, and, uh, sometimes they get false reads.
我問你一件事
Let me ask you something.
如果真確診了呢
What if it ain't okay?
我不能這麼想
I can't think like that.
得想 不然
You gotta, I mean,
真有事該怎麼辦
how you gonna handle it?
我不願意想
I don't wanna go there.
你會愛她嗎
You gonna love her?
你怎麼問得出這種話 洛奇
How you gonna ask me a question like that, Rock?
- 我會 我肯定會愛她 - 那就好
- Yeah, I'm gonna love her. - Good.
阿瑪拉不會覺得自己有缺陷 所以
'Cause she ain't feeling sorry for herself,
你也不該這麼覺得
and you shouldn't either.
這是什麼
You got a little...
拳擊手套
Oh, it's boxing gloves.
- 是吧 - 是
- You got it? - Yeah.
奎迪
恭喜 巴迪·瑪塞勒
是《晚安 月亮》這書 我很喜歡
Goodnight Moon. I love that book.
誰送的 寶貝
Who's that from, babe?
被公認為最強拳壇新人的維克托·德拉戈
The unanimous number one contender Viktor Drago
在他父親的故鄉俄羅斯
has been met with open arms back in Russia,
受到了熱情的歡迎 可謂好事一樁
his father's home, which is nice.
不過現在所有人最關心的一件事是 奎迪哪兒去了
But the question on everyone's mind is, "Where is Creed?"
如果他再不快點選出比賽對手 就有被取消拳王稱號的危險
If he doesn't choose an opponent soon, he risks forfeiting the title
而我想 他恐怕會無法承受這樣的打擊
and personally, I can't imagine him being able to live with that.
怎麼了
You good?
沒事 總算把她哄睡了
Yeah. Finally got her to settle.
我得出去一趟 辦點事情
Hey, I need to get out of the house.
我本來得去工作室的
I was gonna go over to the studio.
我回來之前你能照看她嗎
You mind watching her until I get back?
能 當然能
Yeah, of course.
好
Cool.
好啦 好啦
Okay, okay.
好的
Yeah.
還好嗎
You okay?
我來 我來就好 對
Yeah, I got it. Yeah.
好
Okay.
拜拜
Bye.
寶貝
Baby.
乖 乖 別哭了
Baby, please.
你餓了 對不對 你餓了 沒關係
Hey, you hungry, right? Hey, baby, you hungry?
我是瑪麗·安 有事請留言
It's Mary Anne. Please leave a message.
媽 聽著
Hey, Ma. Listen, listen.
阿瑪拉一直在哭 你能不能告訴我
She won't stop crying. Can you just tell me how to...
告訴我怎麼能讓她不哭
Can you tell me how to make her stop crying?
你聽到就給我回電 好嗎
Call me back when you get this message, okay?
你怎麼啦 乖女兒
Hey, what's up, baby girl?
別哭
Hey, no.
沒事的 寶貝
It's okay, baby. No, no.
別哭 別再哭了
No, don't cry. No, not again, please.
求你了
Please.
你看
No, look, look, look.
看見了嗎
You see that?
看這兒
Look, look, look.
Look.
我在這兒呢
I'm right here.
對不起
I'm sorry.
別哭 來抱抱
Hey. No, no, there you go.
我知道
I know.
最近爸爸表現很糟 我知道
Mmm-hmm. Daddy's being a bitch, I know.
她怎麼樣
How'd you do?
她非常堅強
She's a fighter.
跟她爸爸一樣
Just like her dad.
也跟她媽媽-樣
Just like her mom, too.
我得跟他再打一次
I have to fight him again.
我不想做你的絆腳石
I don't wanna be that person to stop you.
但我也不想最後和你媽媽一樣孤獨
But I don't wanna end up like your mom, alone.
我明白
I feel you.
是嗎
Do you?
我們都已經有孩子了 多尼
And it's not just us anymore, D.
我知道再去自討苦吃一次聽起來很瘋狂
I know it sounds crazy doing all this all over again.
但我不會被輕易擊潰
But this won't be the end of me.
你也不會
Or you.
絕對不會 因為我們一條心
It can't be, 'cause we a team.
上次你擅自應戰就沒跟我一條心
We weren't a team when you took the fight the last time.
你說得對
You right.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我不該讓你受這份罪
I shouldn't have put you through that.
那你何苦呢
Then why?
何苦還要打
Why do it again?
你到底要證明什麼
What do you have to prove?
跟證明什麼無關
It's not about that.
而是人一旦放棄熱愛的事業就會失去自己的價值
You wouldn't be any good to anybody if you didn't do what you love.
會連活都活不下去 對嗎
You wouldn't be able to breathe, right?
所以如果不能好好把這件事做個了斷 那我以後就算廢了
Well, I wouldn't be any good to anybody if I don't handle this the right way.
我需要你的支持
But I need you.
我也捨不得女兒
Both of you.
我一定會贏
I'll beat him.
你只能贏
You better.
這件事你必須好好考慮清楚
You gotta think about this real hard.
你現在可是有家人需要照顧的
You got people that need you now.
正因為這樣我才更不能輸
That's exactly why I can't lose.
巴迪說要比只能在俄羅斯比
Buddy said the fight has to be in Russia.
不然就別比
Take it or leave it.
俄羅斯
Russia?
他們的地盤
On their turf.
那就去俄羅斯
So Russia it is.
你說呢 洛奇
What you think, Rock?
要是最後得靠裁判打分定輸贏 他們是有優勢的
It's a clear advantage if it comes down to a judge's decision.
那就只好把他徹底擊倒 不勞裁判費心了 對嗎
Well, then we can't let it get to a judge's decision, right?
真要命
Oh, shit.
那聯繫巴迪嗎
Call the promoter.
明早五點在這裏訓練嗎
So we train here tomorrow, 5:00 a.m.
不 我有個新的計劃
No, I got other plans.
- 你是說回費城去嗎 - 不
- You mean, you wanna go to Philly? - No.
聽著 你要是想一鼓作氣扭轉 乾坤
Listen, you wanna change things in a big way,
那就必須先讓自己脫胎換骨
then you need to make some big changes.
來這兒練 你逗我嗎
You gotta be messing with me, right?
聽說如果有哪個拳手想從頭來過
Heard this is a place where fighters go,
都會來這兒練
you know, to start over.
讓自己涅槃重生
Get reborn.
怎麼這麼晚才到
What took y'all so long?
找不到地方上廁所嗎
This some wild shit.
是 對我來說簡直是地獄
Yeah, sure looks like hell to me.
既然你之後又要挑戰地獄難度的對手 那就快點適應這裏
Since you're going back to hell, you might as well get used to it.
開始吧
Let's go.
加油干
Go for it.
用力點
Harder.
再用力點
還得用力
Harder!
堅持
Keep going.
脖子練結實
Build that neck.
來 爺們點
Okay, man up.
不用
No.
我沒事
I'm good.
在這兒打就這規矩 先腳碰腳 習慣就好
That's the fight it's gonna be. Toe-to-toe. Get used to it.
開始
Box!
扛住 用身體扛住
Take it to the body.
忍住 要打敗疼痛
Take it! Fight the pain.
還好嗎
You all right?
把腳伸進去 伸進去再來
Get back in there.
保護好自己
Get back in there. Protect yourself.
加油 起來 孩子
Come on, get up, kid.
站起來
Get up.
腳下別停
Keep moving.
這就對了
That's it.
俄羅斯 莫斯科
再過幾分鐘
We're just minutes away from the fight
這場全球矚目的世紀大戰就將開始了
the whole world has been waiting to see.
這一次是阿多尼斯·奎迪與維克托·德拉戈
The rematch between Adonis Creed and Viktor Drago
第二次為爭奪世界重量級拳王開戰
for the heavyweight championship of the world.
賽前有一點值得有提 吉姆
The unique thing about this fight, Jim,
那就是阿多尼斯·奎迪在拳擊博彩中的賠率只有1:25 非常不被看好
is Adonis Creed comes in a 25-to-1 underdog,
他可是衛冕的一方
and he's the champ!
那相信大家都很好奇
Well, it's gonna be fascinating to see
這件事對他踏上拳台後的心態 會有什麼影響
what that does to Creed's mindset as he enters the ring.
德拉戈又會怎麼想呢
Not to mention Drago's.
德拉戈
德拉戈 德拉戈 德拉戈
Drago! Drago! Drago!
德拉戈上場了
And there he is.
先生們 女士們 維克托·德拉戈 現在正向體育場走來
Ladies and gentlemen, Viktor Drago! Making his way into the arena.
雖然還沒有奪得金腰帶 但是在俄羅斯觀眾看來
He does not have the belt, but to everyone here in Russia
甚至在全世界很多觀眾看來
and to many around the world,
他才是真正的重量級拳王
he is the true heavyweight champion.
要上場了 小子
It's time, kid.
奎迪與德拉戈的這一戰無可避免
There was no way Creed could have run from this fight.
因為粉絲的呼聲太高 希望他重返拳台與德拉戈再戰
There was such high demand for Adonis to step back in the ring with Viktor.
我相信伊凡時隔多年回到祖國 應該感覺不錯
And I'm sure Ivan feels good to be back home after all these years.
一路走來
♪ Ran the whole way
一戰到底
♪ Ran the whole thing
永不逃避
♪ Never ran away
絕不恐懼
♪ Never been afraid
永不停歇
♪ Never gonna break
絕不放棄
♪ Never halfway
不知道自己能否承受
♪ I don't know if I can take it
能否承受這一切
♪ I can take it, I can take it anymore
不知道自己能否實現
♪ I don't know if I could do it
如果不是為了最初的那人努力
If it wasn't for who I'd do it for
什麼毫無意義 卻是生財之道
♪ Doesn't make sense But it makes dollars
我願和你一起浪費
♪ And I wanna spend it all with you
和你起對抗世界
♪ Against the world But I'm with you
如果你倒下
♪ I would go to war
我願踏入戰爭
♪ 'Long as you're down
不會讓你失望
♪ Won't let you down
我願踏入戰爭
♪ I would go to war
♪ I would go to war ♪
別忘了你是為什麼要踏上拳台
Remember why you're climbing these steps.
上吧 拳王
Come on up, champ.
終於等到了 吉姆 奎迪與德拉戈火花四濺的二度對決
This is it, Jim. Creed versus Drago part two.
奎迪今晚狀態不錯
Creed looks good tonight,
不過他上次與德拉戈對決時的慘狀
but it's impossible to forget what happened to him
我到現在還感覺歷歷在目
the last time he stepped into the ring with Drago.
他傷痕纍纍 其中最嚴重的 是一根肋骨被打至斷裂
Numerous injuries, not least of all, a nasty broken rib
還有一側腎臟破裂
and a ruptured kidney.
這次他有一大變化
A huge difference in this fight
那就是他請回了著名教練 前拳王洛奇·巴爾博亞作為指導
is he's got former champ Rocky Balboa back in his corner.
有洛奇坐鎮
And Rocky assures everyone
本場比賽奎迪應該會有脫胎換骨的表現
this fight will be very different from its predecessor.
晚上好 女士們先生們 終於等到今晚了
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. This is it.
本次十二回合制的
Twelve rounds of boxing
世界重量級拳王衛冕賽 即將開戰
for the heavyweight championship of the world!
女士們 先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
讓我們為拳手們吶喊吧
let's get ready to rumble!
你能感覺到今晚拳台上一觸即發的緊張感 吉姆
You can feel the nervous energy in the arena tonight, Jim.
奎迪竟然有膽量再次面對
Creed has some courage to get back into the ring
曾經差點終結自己職業生涯的對手
with a man who nearly ended his career.
對拳王之位志在必得的德拉戈
A man who is hungry to be champ.
兩位
Fighters,
我要一場公平乾淨的比賽
I want good, clean fight.
要乾乾淨淨的比賽
我說分開 你們就分開
Break when I tell you to break.
我讓你們退回場角 你們就回到場角
You go to your corner when I tell you to go to your corner.
我說分開 你們就分開
我讓你們退回場角 你們就退回場角
碰拳套 祝你們好運
Touch gloves.
洛奇·巴爾博亞和伊凡·德拉戈
Rocky Balboa and Ivan Drago sharing the ring
時隔三十年再一次站上了同一個拳台
for the first time in 30 years.
所有人都知道 要備戰德拉戈這麼強的對手 只能找洛奇
If anyone knows how to take on a slugger like Drago, it would be Rocky.
你知道你心裏燒著怎樣的火
You know you got the fire in your gut,
而我知道你會在拳台上怎樣活
and I know you'll do what needs to be done.
因為現在 你已經明白自己為什麼而戰
Because now, you know what you're fighting for.
這一次無論如何 都要拿下金腰帶
德拉戈上一次狠狠壓制奎迪的比賽戰術
Viktor overwhelmed Creed's previous game plan,
現在阿多尼斯應該還有陰影
and I think it got in Adonis' head.
你一定能贏
所以我們都非常期待看到洛奇·巴爾博亞的訓練成果
It's gonna be interesting to see how Rocky Balboa has prepared Creed
看他如何幫助奎迪備戰這場激烈對抗
for what is surely to become an all-out brawl.
好了嗎
Ready?
開始
Box.
比賽正式開始
And we're underway.
德拉戈連續打出了兩記勾拳 但奎迪躲開了
Drago comes out swinging with two hooks that Creed avoids.
德拉戈又揮出一記重重的右勾拳
And a big right-hand right out of the gate.
小心右拳 多尼
Watch that right, Donnie.
德拉戈有點意外 奎迪竟然躲開了他的攻擊
Drago a bit surprised as Creed shakes that punch off.
你還愣著幹什麼 繼續攻擊
一記右直拳 德拉戈步步緊逼 不過奎迪並沒有就此退縮
Drago is pressing hard, but Creed is not backing off.
腳下別停
Keep moving, keep moving.
奎迪今晚與德拉戈對打 採取了貼身戰術
Creed working a little bit closer to Drago tonight.
剛才奎迪鬥志昂揚地打出子一套組合拳
That is a vicious combination by Creed.
剛剛德拉戈揮出了右拳
And now a right hand by Drago.
發力了 德拉戈開始向對手反擊了
Here we go, Drago applying pressure.
別進場角 出來 多尼
- Out the corner! - Come on, Donnie!
奎迪一個閃身 離開了場角
Creed manages to slip away.
放馬過來
Let's get it.
怎麼樣
Yeah, what's up?
兩個人在拳台中央周旋
Now they're squaring off in the middle of the ring, toe-to-toe.
互有命中 勢均力敵
Taking blows.
奎迪連續打中對手的臉
Creed staying in his face.
鈴聲響了 激烈的第一回合比賽已經結束了
And there's the bell! As a wild first round comes to an end.
回角落去
Go to your corner.
德拉戈有些挫敗
Drago frustrated.
今晚的奎迪就像換了個人似的 馬克斯
Creed is looking like a different fighter tonight, Max.
很好 就該這樣
- That's it, D! That's it! - Yes!
看誰還給德拉戈加油
Oh, yeah, who's saying Drago now, though?
荒地裏那些苦沒白吃吧 是
See, all that work in the desert paid off, right?
你得手了 他就得想辦法了
Yeah, you got him. You got him thinking.
他本來沒想到你會這麼打
He wasn't expecting what you're bringing.
下一回合他攻勢會更猛 但你準備好了
Now, he's gonna bring the heat the next round, but you're ready for it.
我之前是怎麼訓練你的
給我把他打趴下
他右拳用得最多
He overextends his right hand.
你先把拳頭擋住
You gonna counter with the right
再用左拳擊垮他 懂了嗎
and crack him with the left. You got that?
他出右拳 我就出左拳
Extend the right, crack him with the left.
他絕對想不到這招 你爸當初就是這麼對付我的
He'll never expect it. His old man did the same thing to me.
據我剛才的觀察 馬克斯
One early observation, Max.
我覺得奎迪今晚在抵抗德拉戈的組合拳時
I think Creed is withstanding Drago's combinations
表現得比上一場要好太多了
much better tonight than in the first fight.
開始
Box.
第二回合比賽開始
And round two begins.
德拉戈揮出了強勁的左勾拳
Drago with a huge left hook.
接著右手一記重拳
And a big right hand.
德拉戈又發起一輪猛攻 現在把奎迪逼到圍繩邊了
Drago on the attack again, now driving Creed back into the ropes.
他一直在出右拳 小心右拳
He's overextending the right! Watch the right!
奎迪左右開弓 重拳出擊
A right and a left for Creed.
出右拳給假動作
好一記上勾拳 奎迪抱住了德拉戈
Huge uppercut has Creed holding on now.
德拉戈擺脫了 並將奎迪逼進場角
Drago throws him off into the corner.
- 離開場角 - 快離開場角
- Get out of that corner! - Get out of the corner!
德拉戈把奎迪摔在了拳台上
And Drago throws Creed to the canvas.
停停停
你在幹什麼
你要幹什麼
這是幹什麼呢
What's going on?
上次比賽也是這樣
Shades of the first fight,
不過這一次德拉戈稍微克制了一點
but Drago showing restraint this time.
還行嗎
You good?
行 沒問題
Yes, I'm good.
趕緊幹掉他
- 開始 - 比賽短暫中止之後 德拉戈徹底爆發了
- Box. - Drago explodes from the break.
奎迪倒地了
And Creed is down!
他沒擋住這一連串颶風般的重拳
A flurry of heavy shots!
德拉戈的力量簡直是太驚人了
Drago's power is just incredible.
三
Three.
四
Four.
等夠八秒 等夠八秒再起來
Take the eight count. Take the full eight.
奎迪正趴在地上 抓緊時間調整
Creed taking his time on the canvas.
六
Six.
趴著別動 深呼吸
Stay down! Breathe!
奎迪聽從了洛奇的指示 因為洛奇曾有過類似的比賽經歷
He's listening to Rocky, who has been in this situation before.
八
Eight.
就在讀秒結束前 奎迪站起來了
And Creed is back on his feet. Beats the count.
- 好了嗎 - 好了 開始吧
- Ready? - Yeah, let's go.
開始
Box.
纏住他 別跟他打 纏住他
Tie him up. Don't fight him. Tie him up.
德拉戈重整旗鼓 再次猛攻
Drago is right back at it.
剛剛一個擊倒 加上最後的連續重拳
So, with the knockdown and those hard shots at the end,
這一回合 德拉戈的贏面明顯要大於奎迪
that round clearly goes to Viktor Drago.
而且能感覺到他的攻勢一波比一波猛
And you could just feel he's gaining momentum.
這次本來就是場硬仗 對吧
You knew this was gonna be a war, right?
你來之前就知道了
You knew that going in there.
從現在起拼的 就是誰更想贏
From now on, it's who wants it more,
誰的意志更堅定
and who's got more heart.
第三回合
打得好
別讓他打垮你 你在外圍轉只能挨打
Don't let him crack you. You stay on the outside, you're gonna get hurt.
近身對打才能打敗他
You stay on the inside, you'll tear him up.
關鍵是得向他施壓
I'm telling you, it's all about pressure.
如果想讓對方痛苦 自己得先忍受痛苦
If you wanna give pain, you gotta be willing to take the pain.
來啊
Come on!
很好
- Yes! - Yes!
金腰帶應該是我們的
可現在你要保不住它了
第四回合 又是一個殘酷激烈的回合
Round four is another brutal display
奎迪被動地受著德拉戈的連續重擊
as Creed takes a lot of punishment from Drago.
德拉戈絲毫沒有放緩自己的攻勢
Drago is not slowing down.
鈴響之後 還對奎迪使出了一記重拳
Landing a big shot after the bell.
你們是怎麼回事
What is your problem?
第五回合
這兩位殘暴的對抗還在繼續 吉姆
The violent chess match continues, Jim.
奎迪又一次被擊倒了
Oh, and Creed is down again.
多尼 起來
Donnie, get up.
德拉戈明顯佔據了上風 不過奎迪也沒想放棄
Drago clearly dominating this fight, but Creed will not give up.
他這幾回合可是受了不少罪
He is taking a lot of punishment.
你就貼身緊逼 看著我
You gotta stay in his face. Look at me.
你要做的就是貼身緊逼
You gotta stay in his face.
一旦你等到機會 就全力出擊
And when you see an opportunity, you go after it.
第六回合
這就對了
There you are!
德拉戈的節奏亂了
Drago is cut now.
第八回合結束
As we enter round eight,
比賽進行到這個階段 超乎我們所有人的預料
we are deeper into this fight than anyone expected.
奎迪自知比分落後 開始逼自己發動進攻
Creed must sense he's behind. He's trying to force the action.
很好 兒子
Yes, baby!
今晚我們一路看著阿多尼斯·奎迪
What we are seeing tonight is Adonis Creed
站上拳台正面迎擊實力非同凡響的維克托·德拉戈
standing up to the awesome power of Viktor Drago.
他絲毫沒有退縮
He's not going anywhere.
再把他放倒一次
維克托看上去很累 馬克斯
Viktor Drago looks tired, Max.
要知道之前他打職業拳賽的時候 從來不必打第四回合
Keep in mind, he's never had to go past the 4th round in a professional fight.
- 他在幹什麼 - 扣分啊 裁判
- Hey! What was that? - Take the point, ref!
德拉戈連出兩記重拳
And Drago drops Creed
又讓奎迪倒在了拳台上
- with two nasty body shots. - Come on!
- 哪有拽著人打的 - 一
- He held him and hit him. - One.
維克托拽住對手攻擊 卻僥倖逃過了判罰
Viktor holding and maybe getting away with something there.
可能是裁判沒有看清
The ref must not have seen it.
過來
Come on.
我看洛奇·巴爾博亞得考慮是不是該認輸了 吉姆
I think Rocky Balboa has a decision to make here, Jim.
他比任何人都清楚
He knows better than anyone
三十年前他遇到同樣的情況時 是什麼樣的結局
how this same story played out three decades ago.
多尼 跟我說話
Donnie, Donnie, talk to me.
多尼
Donnie.
你的肋骨
Your ribs?
斷了嗎
You think it's broke?
幹掉他
你想怎麼辦 多尼
What do you wanna do, Donnie?
要我認輸嗎
You wanna call it?
我想也不是
I didn't think so.
上 下 上 下
接下來他會窮追不捨
Now he's gonna come after you,
攻擊你受傷的肋骨 讓它徹底斷掉
and he's gonna try to break on that rib some more.
但沒關係
But that's okay.
因為你享受疼痛 你扛得住
'Cause you like the pain. You can take it.
為什麼 因為你很強大
You know why? Because you're dangerous.
- 我很強大 - 說得沒錯
- I'm dangerous. - That's right.
還有十秒
Ten seconds out.
現在到了第十回合的比賽
Now here we go with round ten
這場比賽已經成了一場艱苦的拉鋸戰
of what has become a war of attrition.
- 目前計分牌顯示德拉戈暫時領先 - 但奎迪 他完全沒打算認輸
Drago seemingly ahead on the scorecards, but Creed refusing to back down.
就這麼打 多尼 很好
That's it, Donnie. Good.
奎迪現在已經是使出了渾身的力氣
Creed using whatever he has left in the tank.
德拉戈在集中攻擊他的身體
Drago working the body.
纏住他
Tie him up!
奎迪再次被擊倒在地
And down goes Creed again.
這場比賽可能要到此為止了
And this could be the end of the fight.
快認輸吧 別死撐了
起來 多尼
Get up, D.
沒有人能抗得住德拉戈那樣的重拳
No man should be able to fight through that beating,
但阿多尼斯·奎迪靠意志再次站了起來 奎迪
but Adonis Creed wills himself off the canvas.
- 你叫什麼 - 奎迪
- What's your name? - Creed.
你叫什麼
What's your name?
奎迪
Creed!
開始
Box!
阿多尼斯·奎迪知道 維克托·德拉戈是他必須跨越的障礙
Adonis Creed knows there is no way around Viktor Drago.
他一定要攻克他
He has to go through him.
重錘
Dig!
重錘 重錘
Dig! Dig!
奎迪突然像多了個馬達一樣
Creed suddenly finding another gear!
加油
Come on!
德拉戈有些站不穩了
Drago's on his heels.
德拉戈被擊倒了
And down goes Drago!
這就對了 就該這樣
That's it! That's right!
拳台上的局勢瞬間扭轉了 一
What a wild turn of events.
站起來
二
Two.
多尼 等他一起來 就乘勝追擊
Donnie, he gets up, you go after him.
三
Three.
四
Four.
五
Five.
- 六 - 德拉戈及時站起來了
- Six. - Drago beats the count.
真不敢相信 這兩位到這一刻居然還能站得住
I can't believe either of these guys are still on their feet.
開始
Box.
德拉戈在比分上應該是大幅領先 他只要不被擊倒在地
Drago seemingly so far ahead on points, he just needs to stay upright
撐到最後就能贏
and make it to the end.
奎通再次進攻 讓德拉戈在圍繩邊動彈不得
Here comes Creed again, driving Drago back into the ropes.
重錘 重錘 打倒他
- Dig! Dig! Dig! - Yeah!
加油 把他擊倒
Come on, take him down!
加油 寶貝
Come on, baby.
維克托·德拉戈被擊倒在地
And Viktor Drago is down!
第二次了
Again!
這場比賽局勢變化太大了
What a turn this fight has taken.
奎迪已經疼得直不起腰了
Creed doubled over in pain
而德拉戈正努力從拳台上爬起來
as Drago tries to pick himself up off the floor.
站起來
德拉戈拼盡了全力 在讀秒結束前站了起來
Drago summons the strength, manages to make the count.
他們還在揮動看拳頭 馬克斯
They're still swinging, Max.
奎迪還在持續不斷地攻擊
Creed continuing to connect.
這場面已經讓人不忍心看下去了 吉姆
And this is becoming hard to watch, Jim.
在我看來德拉戈已經無力反抗了
I don't think Drago has anything left,
但他就是死活不肯放棄
but he refuses to give up.
好心 比賽結束
And that's it! It's over!
老德拉戈作為教練 扔毛巾認輸了
Drago's corner throws in the towel.
而阿多尼斯·奎迪衛冕了拳王之位
And Adonis Creed defends his title.
也守住了名譽
Defends his name.
更創造出了屬於自己的傳奇
Creates his own legacy.
他依舊是手握金腰帶的世界重量級拳王
He is still the heavyweight champion of the world.
現場的俄羅斯觀眾 此刻也都紛紛起立為這位美國拳手鼓掌喝彩
And the Russian crowd is standing and cheering for the American fighter.
比安卡呢 比安
Where's B at? Where's B?
慢點 慢點
Easy, easy, easy.
讓開 大家都讓開一點 讓他透口氣
Hey, back up. Everybody back up. We need air.
好了
Yeah.
- 我們做到了 - 我們做到了
- We did it. - We did it.
沒關係
- 沒關係 - 我們回家
- Let's go home. - Let's go, D.
我沒事 媽 我沒事
I'm good, Ma. I'm good.
- 我做到了 - 你是做到了
- I did it. I did it. - You did it.
大叔
Hey, Unc.
現在是你的時代
It's your time.
退後
Hey, okay, back up.
阿波羅·奎迪
老爸
What's up, Pops?
我很抱歉一直沒來看你
I'm sorry it took me so long to come see you.
我不知道跟你說什麼好
I'm not sure how this is supposed to go. Um...
我猜你應該想知道 媽媽過得很不錯
I guess I should tell you that Mom's doing pretty good.
你知道她很堅強
You know, she's holding up.
洛奇也是
So is Rocky.
溫哥華出租
麻煩你了
- Thanks a lot. - Thank you.
他也很堅強
He's a tough dude.
我能明白你為什麼喜歡他
I can see why you liked him.
我也明白你為什麼想跟他較量
I also see why you wanted to fight him, too.
聽著
Look, um,
我就是想來告訴你
I just came here to tell you that...
我證明了自己
That I did it.
但我不是為你
But I didn't do it for you.
也不是求別人認同
Or because of them.
我這麼做 只因為這是我的戰鬥
I did it because it was my fight.
當我踏上那個拳台
And when I stepped into that ring,
我代表的不只是自己
it wasn't just about me.
你好
Hello.
你就是羅根吧
You must be Logan.
對 你是誰
Yes. Who are you?
羅根 是誰來了
Lo, who is it?
有些事只能我們親力親為
Sometimes we think we have to do it all on our own.
你好 羅伯特
Hey, Robert.
但我們沒有去做
But we don't.
我正好在附近辦點事
I was just around in the neighborhood, so...
這是你爺爺
This is your grandfather.
你長得真像你爸爸的媽媽
You look just like his mother.
是啊
Yeah, I know.
我想介紹個人給你
I wanna introduce you to somebody.
你想進來坐坐麼
Do you wanna come inside?
好
Yeah.
來抱一個
Give me that.
- 那是個球麼 - 是的
- Is that a ball? - Yeah.
- 來玩我扔你接吧 - 好
- Wanna play catch? - Yes.
來吧
There you go.
這位
This
是你的孫女 阿瑪拉
is your granddaughter. Amara.
那位是你的爺爺
Say what's up to Pop-Pop.
奎迪